Allyson Kragel

510 33rd Avenue Marion, Iowa 52302 319-540-1168 <u>akragel@gmail.com</u>

Marketing & Communications Professional

Creative professional with expertise in all aspects of successful marketing, advertising, public relations, event planning and management. Demonstrated ability to manage and motivate cohesive teams to achieve results. Excel in managing multiple projects concurrently with strong detail, problem solving and follow through capabilities. Source vendors, negotiate contracts and manage budgets. Superb written and oral communication, interpersonal and organizational skills. First class client and teaming skills.

Skill Sets

Creative Marketing Planning & Execution Budget Management Market Research & Competition Analysis Marketing Measurement Branding Digital Media Strategy
Promotional & Journalistic Writing
Public Relations Strategy
Event Management
Crisis Communication

Professional Experience

Senior Marketing Coordinator 2013 to present Kirkwood Community College, Cedar Rapids, Iowa

- Create and execute marketing plans for grant-funded programs.
- Instituted and maintain brand identity for Iowa workforce development programs.
- Write, produce videos and coordinate design for credit class promotion; continuing education; tuition assistance and career pathway programs for low income individuals; and high school completion, including adult basic education and English as a second language.
- Write college-wide communications plan, establishing messaging and voice.
- Make cost-effective advertising buys.
- Develop and implement digital strategy, including CRM, SMS, SEO and social media.
- Utilize Google Analytics to create metrics for marketing measurement.
- Update website content.
- Perform media relations and orchestrate public relations events.
- From 2013 to 2016, increased web traffic by 443% for career pathways and 339% for tuition assistance.
- Increased number of high school completion students served by 8% from 2014 to 2016.

Marketing Consultant 2006 to 2016 $\,$

Mercy Medical Center, Cedar Rapids, Iowa

- Developed and executed marketing and advertising plans for hand and oral hygiene, human resources, imaging services, obstetrics, orthopedics, staff initiatives, substance abuse treatment and sports care.
- Directed photo shoots and videos.

Allyson Kragel [continued]

510 33rd Avenue Marion, Iowa 52302 319-540-1168 akragel@gmail.com

- Streamlined employee recognition events, boosting attendance by 95%.
- Wrote speeches for hospital executives.
- Conducted qualitative research for the design of the Hall-Perrine Cancer Center.
- Initiated Mercy's partnership with Lindale Mall to claim sole health care advertising and promotional rights.

Marketing Coordinator 2005 to 2006

MercyCare Community Physicians, Cedar Rapids, Iowa

- Member of the organization's leadership team.
- Single-handedly developed and executed marketing and advertising plans for the 71physician network, including two urgent care and one specialty clinic.
- Allocated a \$300,000 marketing budget, including advertising, print collateral, special events and ad agency services.
- Responsible for all public relations activities, including media relations.
- Launched a new website, writing and maintaining all content.
- Managed ad agency services for print and electronic advertising campaigns.

Marketing Director 1991 to 1996

Sycamore Mall, Iowa City, Iowa

- Second in command of mall management.
- Managed the customer service center and seasonal employees.
- Developed and executed marketing and advertising plans for a regional shopping center.
- Wrote and allocated a \$150,000 marketing budget, including advertising, print collateral, special events and freelance design services.
- Negotiated vendor contracts.
- Overhauled the gift certificate program, increasing sales by 150%.
- Performed media relations and received extensive crisis communication training.

Education

Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism and Mass Communication

Minor: Business

Emphasis: Advertising

Awards

Seven ADDYs for advertising excellence 1991 to 2001, Advertising Federation of Cedar Rapids Service Person of the Year 2000, Advertising Federation of Cedar Rapids